Guide to the Samuel L. Clemens Papers, 1796-1984 (bulk 1853-1909)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series HH. Charles L. Webster Correspondence Received
  - Letter from S.S. Cox. House of Representatives, 12 Feb 1888 (31.19 [HH.177])
  - Billing from Bauman Brothers, 22 Mar 1888 (31.20 [HH.178])
  - Letter from Col. M.V. Sheridan, Washington, DC, 14 June 1888 (31.21 [HH.179])
  - Letter from Dr. Cornelius A. Logan, 5 Mar 1889 (31.22 [HH.180])
  - Letter from Rutherford B. Hayes, Spiegel Grove, Fremont, O., 11 Mar 1889 (31.23 [HH.181])
  - Letter from Elizabeth B. Custer, 148 E. 18 St., 21 Jan 1889 (31.24 [HH.182])
  - Letter from Mrs. Custer, 19 May 1889 (31.25 [HH.183])
  - Letter from Mrs. Custer, 25 May 1889 (31.26 [HH.184])
  - Letter from Mrs. Custer, 20 July 1889 (31.27 [HH.185])
  - Envelope marked "Beecher's Letter,", undated (31.28 [HH.186])
  - New York. Receipt for $5,000 rec'd from [Charles] L. Webster and Co., advance on autobiography, endorsed by Henry Ward Beecher, 9 Feb 1887 (31.29 [HH.187])
  - Letter from Mrs. H.W. Beecher, Brooklyn, 3 Mar 1887 (31.30 [HH.188])
  - Part of a letter addressed to Henry Ward Beecher, undated (31.31 [HH.189])
  - Letter from Henry Ward Beecher, 16 Feb 1887 (31.32 [HH.190])
  - Advertisement, The Stowe House, Brunswick, Maine, undated (31.33 [HH.191])
- Series JJ. Charles L. Webster Correspondence Concerning General U.S. Grant's Memoirs
  - Letter from Gen. Grant, NYC, 14 Jan 1881 (31.34 [JJ.1])
  - Letter from Gen. Grant, 14 Mar 1885 (31.35 [JJ.2])
  - Letter from Gen. Grant, 3. E. 66 St., NY, 14 Apr 1885 (31.36 [JJ.3])
  - Letter from Gen. Grant, 2 May 1885 (31.37 [JJ.4])
  - Six facsimile signatures of Gen. Grant to be used in Memoirs, 29 Apr 1885 (31.38 [JJ.5])
  - This book is dedicated to The American Volunteer U.S. Grant, undated (31.39 [JJ.6])
  - These volumes are dedicated to the American soldier and sailor U.S. Grant, undated (31.40 [JJ.7])
  - Original second dedication of Gen. Grant's Memoirs in his own handwriting, undated (31.41 [JJ.8])
  - Letter from Gen. Grant, New York, 2 May 1885 (31.42 [JJ.9])
  - Letter from Gen. Grant, Mt. McGregor, NY, 4 July 1885 (31.43 [JJ.10])
  - Letter from Gen. Grant, Mt. McGregor, NY, 15 July 1885 (31.44 [JJ.11])
  - Pencil note in Gen. Grant's handwriting from his last days, undated (31.45 [JJ.12])
  - Mrs. Grant will be home this evening, 3 E. 66 St., NY, undated (31.46 [JJ.13])
  - Card: Mrs. Grant wished to call Mrs. Webster's attention, 3 E. 66 St., NY, undated (31.47 [JJ.14])
  - Gen. Grant's widow's receipt for $200,000 royalty check signed Julia D. Grant, 27 Feb 1886 (31.48 [JJ.15])
  - Copy $200,000 check of [Charles] L. Webster and Co. to Mrs. Grant, undated (31.49 [JJ.16])
  - Clipping, $150,000 check of [Charles] L. Webster Co. to Mrs. Grant, undated (31.50 [JJ.17])
  - [Charles] L. Webster's "Museum"note re: $1,000 check to Gen. Grant on signing contract for his "Personal Memoirs,", undated (31.51 [JJ.18])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, New York, 18 June 1886 (31.52 [JJ.19])
  - Letter from Julia D. Grant, Elbron, NJ, 21 June 1886 (31.53 [JJ.20])
  - Alexander and Green, 120 Broadway, NY, 13 Apr 1885 (31.54 [JJ.21])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, undated (31.55 [JJ.22])
  - "Dear Webster, The bearer Mrs. Lewis Deart…", undated (31.56 [JJ.23])
  - "Dear Webster, I haven't received the maps…", undated (31.57 [JJ.24])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, 3 E. 66 St., New York, 26 Nov 1885 (31.58 [JJ.25])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, 3 E. 66 St., NYC, 3 Dec 1884 (31.59 [JJ.26])
  - Rec'd New York from [Charles] L. Webster and Co. $150 on account for engraving…, 19 Mar 1885 (31.60 [JJ.27])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, Mt. McGregor, 8 July 1885 (31.61 [JJ.28])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, Mt. McGregor, 8 July 1885 (31.62 [JJ.29])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, Mt. McGregor, 18 July 1885 (31.63 [JJ.30])
  - Letter from Karl Gerhardt, sculptor, 21 Dec 1885 (31.64 [JJ.31])
  - Letter from Col. F.D. Grant, NY, 16 Dec 1885 (31.65 [JJ.32])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, NY, 16 Dec 1885 (31.66 [JJ.33])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, NY, 18 Dec 1885 (31.67 [JJ.34])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, NY, undated (31.68 [JJ.35])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, NY, 13 Apr 1886 (31.69 [JJ.36])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, NY, 15 May 1886 (31.70 [JJ.37])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, 3 E. 66 St., NY, 9 Dec 1886 (31.71 [JJ.38])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, NY, 5 Mar 1887 (31.72 [JJ.39])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, 3 E. 66 St., NY, May 10 (15?), 1887 (32.1 [JJ.40])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, 20 July 1887 (32.2 [JJ.47])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, 3 E. 66 St., NY, 29 Mar 1889 (32.3 [JJ.48])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, undated (32.4 [JJ.49])
  - Letter from F.D. Grant, undated (32.5 [JJ.50])
  - Letter from U.S. Grant, Jr. Salem Center, Westchester County, NY, 5 July 1885 (32.6 [JJ.51])
  - Letter from U.S. Grant, Jr. The Union League Club, undated (32.7 [JJ.52])
  - Letter from U.S. Grant, Jr. 3 E. 66 St., NYC, 24 May 1888 (32.8 [JJ.53])
  - Letter from Jesse Grant, 3 E. 66 St., NYC, Feb. 26 (32.9 [JJ.54])
  - Letter from Ida H. Grant, 3 Feb 1887 (32.10 [JJ.55])
  - Letter from Mr. J.R. Grant, East Lyme, Ct., 2 June1886 (32.11 [JJ.56])
  - Letter from Lizzie C. Grant, 3 E. 66 St., NYC, Oct. 18 (32.12 [JJ.57])
  - Letter from Lizzie C. Grant, 3 E. 66 St., NYC, 11 Nov 1886 (32.13 [JJ.58])
  - Letter from Gen. Adam Badeau, 28 E. 17 St., NYC, Feb. 17 (32.14 [JJ.59])
  - Palmer House, Chicago, Thirteenth Annual Banquet of the Society of the Army of the Tennessee, 13 Nov 1879 (32.15 [JJ.60])
  - Letter from Brig. Gen. C.C. Augur, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, 7 Apr 1885 (32.16 [JJ.61])
  - Letter from W.D. Howells, 302 Beacon St., Boston, 3 July 1885 (32.17 [JJ.62])
  - Letter from J.P. Newman, Mt. McGregor, 13 July 1885 (32.18 [JJ.63])
  - Letter from Gen. Ely S. Parker, New York, 15 Oct 1885 (32.19 [JJ.64])
  - Letter from R.W. Gilder,. Editorial Dept., Century Magazine, 16 Dec 1885 (32.20 [JJ.65])
  - Letter from John W. Chadwick, 826 Carlton Ave., Brooklyn, NY, 4 Dec 1885 (32.21 [JJ.66])
  - Letter from unidentified correspondent, NY, 16 Dec 1874 (32.22 [JJ.66A])
  - Letter from Roswell Smith, President Century Co., 21 Dec 1885 (32.23 [JJ.67])
  - Letter from J.B. Mills, American Exchange in Paris, 3 Mar 1886 (32.24 [JJ.68])
  - Remnant of letter addressed to Messrs C.L. Webster, undated (32.25 [JJ.69])
  - Memorial Day Committee, invitation to decoration of Grant's Tomb, 22 Apr 1886 (32.26 [JJ.70])
  - Memorial Day Service, 31 May 1886 (32.27 [JJ.71])
  - U.S. Grant Post, G.A.R. Invitation to decoration Grant's Tomb, 31 May 1886 (32.28 [JJ.72])
  - Pass, [Charles] L. Webster Esq. on Head Quarters Steamer and to the Ceremonies at Gen. Grant's Tomb, Riverside Park, 31 May 1886 (32.29 [JJ.73])
  - Letter from Cardinal Gibbons, Baltimore, 13 Nov 1886 (32.30 [JJ.74])
  - Letter from R.W. Johnson, Editorial Dept., Century Magazine, 20 Nov 1886 (32.31 [JJ.75])
  - Letter from R.W. Johnson, Editorial Dept., Century Magazine, 18 Dec 1886 (32.32 [JJ.76])
  - Letter from R.W. Johnson, Editorial Dept., Century Magazine, 21 Jan 1887 (32.33 [JJ.77])
  - Letter from C.A. Dana, The Sun, NY, 22 Dec 1886 (32.34 [JJ.78])
  - Letter from Horace Porter, New York, 12 Mar 1887 (32.35 [JJ.79])
  - Letter from Horace Porter, New York, 19 Mar 1887 (32.36 [JJ.80])
  - Letter from J.H. Douglas, 33 W. 16 St., NY, 13 Oct 1888 (32.37 [JJ.81])
  - Letter from Lloyd Lewis to S.C. Webster, Newberry Library, Chicago, 19 Apr 1947 (32.38 [JJ.82])
  - Letter from Lloyd Lewis and copy NY Tribune interviews with Charles L. Webster, The Chicago Sun, 2 Apr 1947, 28 July 1885 (32.39 [JJ.83])
  - Mark Twain, an Exhibition, The Huntington Library, San Marino, Ca…, 1947 (32.40 [JJ.84])
  - Last photograph taken of Gen. Grant, Mt. McGregor, undated (32.41[JJ.85])
  - Photograph of Gen. Grant taken 4 days before his death, 22 July 1885 (32.42 [JJ.86])
  - Photograph of Gerhardt's bust of Gen. Grant, undated (32.43 [JJ.87])
  - Photograph of Gen. Grant, 5 June 1868 (32.44 [JJ.88])
  - Photograph of Gen. Grant, 5 June 1868 (32.45 [JJ.89])
  - Engraving, U.S. Grant, 2d Lt., copyright 1885 (32.46 [JJ.90])
  - Photograph Gen. Grant's funeral, copyright 1885 (32.47 [JJ.91])
  - Engraving: Ligby Prison as it appeared 23 Aug 1863, copyright 1882 (32.48 [JJ.92])
  - 2 photographs, Appomattox Court House; and Field where Gen. B. met Gen. Grant, undated (32.49 [JJ.93])
  - Front view, McLean House where Lee surrendered, undated (32.50 [JJ.94])
  - End view McLean House, undated (32.51 [JJ.95])
- Series KK. "Personal Memoirs" of General U.S. Grant Manuscript
  - "With the troops on Missionary Ridge…" (32.52 [KK.1])
  - "3/ retreat Burnside relief was soon effected…" (32.53 [KK.2])
  - "On the 15th of November, while I was still at Holly Springs, I sent word to Sherman…" (p.427, Vol. I.) (32.54 [KK.3])
  - "McPherson, after crossing the big Black, to the right of Jackson and Vicksburg Rd…" ( p.528-529, Vol. I.) (32.55 [KK.4])
  - "Hooker's position in Lookout Valley was absolutely essential…" (p.56-57, Vol. II) (32.56 [KK.5])
  - "My recollection is that my first orders for the battle of Chattanooga…" (p.88, Vol. II) (32.57 [KK.6])
  - "In this battle the Union Army numbered in round figures about 60,000 men…" (p.95-96-97, Vol. II) (32.58 [KK.7])
  - …"hundreds, if not thousands, who deserted but little reliance could be placed in this report…" (p.97, Vol. II) (32.59 [KK.8])
  - "There has always been a great conflict of opinion…" (p.500-501-502, Vol. II) (32.60 [KK.9])
  - "… of machinery to increase the products of a dog's labor in the shop…" (p.502-503, Vol. II) (32.61 [KK.10])
  - "… have been an officer directly after the war…" (p.503-504, Vol. II) (32.62 [KK.11])
- Series LL. Sir Charles L. Webster, Knight of the Order of Piano (Pius), Vatican, Rome Correspondence
  - Envelope, "Knighthood Matter," C.L. Webster. Translation of Latin brief and Italian letter, undated (33.1 [LL.1])
  - No.72208. Letter from M. Cardinal Rompolla, Rome, 7 Nov 1887 (33.2 [LL.2])
  - Handwritten translation, letter from M. Cardinal Rompolla, 7 Nov 1887 (33.3 [LL.3])
  - Letter from M. Cardinal Ledochowski, 1 Oct 1887 (33.4 [LL.4])
  - Letter from Archbishop Corrigan, New York, 7 Dec 1887 (33.5 [LL.5])
  - Uniforms of Officers of the Pontifical Court, undated (33.6 [LL.6])
  - Translation: "For one complete uniform of the Knight of the Order of Piano,", 17 Mar 1888 (33.7 [LL.7])
  - Clipping: NY Tribune, 11 Mar 1885 (33.8 [LL.8])
  - Letter to Charles Webster from St. Francis Xavier's College, 6 Dec 1887 (33.9 [LL.9])
  - Milan Cathedral panorama engraving, with notes on back in handwriting of Charles L. Webster, undated (33.10 [LL.10])
  - Photograph of an unidentified cathedral, undated (33.11 [LL.11])
  - Photograph of Archbishop of Vienna, 26 Feb 1887 (33.12 [LL.12])
  - Photographic copy of invitation to audience with Pope Leo XIII, issued to Mr. Mrs. Webster, undated (33.13 [LL.13])
- Series MM. Estate of Charles L. Webster
  - For the Pope, Rome, Italy, with complements and regards of F.D. Grant, undated (33.14 [MM.1])
  - Letter from Dr. Bernard O'Reilly, 1051 Park Avenue, New York, 28 Apr 1891 (33.15 [MM.2])
  - Estate of Charles L. Webster, Letters Testamentary, 1 June 1891 (33.16 [MM.3])
  - Letter from S.L. Clemens (also B.613), Farmington Ave., Hartford, 26 Apr 1891 (33.17 [MM.4])
  - Letter from Miss Margaret Sutherland Wiley, 285 Pleasant St., Pasadena, 24 Oct 1944 (33.18 [MM.5])
  - Inter-Strasse, Historic Charles L. Webster Residence at Fredonia, NY, undated; (clipping) (33.19 [MM.6])
- Series NN. William Luther Webster Correspondence
  - 24 Stanhope Rd, Highgate N.6, London, Mar 1945; (incorrectly labeled NN.2 on microfilm) (33.20 [NN.1])
  - American Consulate General, 1 Grosvenor Sq., London, 31 Aug 1943 (33.21 [NN.2])
  - Photograph Civil Defense Unit, London, 1943 (33.22 [NN.3])
  - Pen and ink drawing of an oriental carving, drawn by WLW, 17 Feb 1899 (33.23 [NN.4])
  - William Luther Webster photograph, undated (33.24 [NN.5])
- Series OO. Samuel Charles Webster Correspondence
  - Book review, Uncle James' Shoes, Doris and Samuel Webster, Century publisher, undated (33.25 [OO.1])
  - Letter from Bernard DeVoto, Harvard University, 1 Feb 1944 (33.26 [OO.2])
  - Letter from Charles W. Morton, Atlantic Monthly Editor, Boston, 1 Aug 1944 (33.27 [OO.3])
  - Letter from Stanley Salmen, Atlantic Monthly Press, Boston, 13 Dec 1946 (33.28 [OO.4])
  - Letter from Bernard DeVoto, The Mark Twain papers, 47 Widener Library, 6 Jan 1947 (33.29 [OO.5])
  - Letter from Edith R. Mirrielees, The Pacific Spectator, 12 Dec 1949 (33.30 [OO.6])
  - The only reliable account of "The Celebrated Jumping Frog of Calaveras County,", undated (33.31 [OO.7])
  - Samuel C. Webster burial permit, date of death 24 Mar 1962 (33.32 [OO.8])
  - Samuel C. Webster obituaries: NY Times, Wilmington Journal, Danbury News, Waterbury Republican, Mar-Apr 1962 (33.33 [OO.9])
  - Samuel C. Webster photograph, undated (33.34 [OO.10])
- Series PP. Photographs (not microfilmed)
  - Henry Ward Beecher (33.35 [PP.1])
  - Fred J. Hall (33.36 [PP.1])
  - W.D. Howells (33.37 [PP.2])
  - Webster House, Fredonia - Exterior (33.38 [PP.2])
  - Webster House, Fredonia - Dining Room (33.39 [PP.2])
  - Webster House, Fredonia - Parlor (33.40 [PP.2])
  - Webster House, Fredonia - Library (33.41 [PP.2])
  - 3 Websters and a neighbor in the Library of the Webster House, Fredonia (33.42 [PP.2])
  - Samuel Webster and Pelican (33.43)
  - Samuel L. Clemens by Gessford, 1904 (Box 37)
  - Negatives (33.44)
- QQ. Ephemera (not microfilmed)
  - Sketches, images from printed material and postcards (Box 36)
  - Clay "indian pipe" (Box 36)
  - Program for Vassar Founder's Day at which SLC gave two "Select readings (Box 36)
- Series RR. Framed Portraits
  - Painting of Henry Clemens, undated (Framed Storage 2.2)
  - Painting of Jane Clemens, undated (Framed Storage 2.2)
  - Mark Twain, lithograph of a painting by Spiridon, circa 1901 (Framed Storage 2.1)
  - Painting of Pamela Clemens Moffett, undated (Framed Storage 2.1)
  - Painting of William A. Moffett, undated (Framed Storage 2.2)
- Use Copies of Fragile Correspondence
  - Use copies of fragile correspondence for sections A - MM, (copies) (Box 34)